<https://github.com/ZhukovGreen>

- [X] Czech Republic, Roznov pod Radhostem
- [X] [zhukovgreen.io@gmail.com] (mailto:zhukovgreen.io@gmail.com)
- [X] +420774081898

Software engineer and machine learning engineer with more than 4 years of experience.

Interested in web applications, DevOps, infrastructure automation, and bots. Compliment projects with machine learning, growing as a professional, learning new technologies, experimenting and building interesting products.

```
# Tech stack
```

```
    Linux operating systems

    Containerization, distributed systems, cloud computing (Docker, AWS,

Kubernetes)
 Software development (
    web, web applications, microservices, apis, bots,
    testing, code linting,
)
  Backend developer (
    python, aiohttp, numpy, pandas, scipy, pytorch,
    keras, scikit-learn, xgboost, opencv, freecad, aiogram
)
 Automation (
    CI/CD, Gitlab CI, Circle CI, Ansible, Python, docker-compose,
    Kubernetes, Vagrant,
 Other tools (
    shell scripting, git, docker, gitlab, postgresql, redis, celery, openapi,
    swagger, pre-commit

    vim, vim scripting

# Free time
I contribute to open-source projects (i.e.
<https://github.com/cr0hn/aiohttp-cache>,
<https://github.com/webknjaz/docker-freecad-cli>,
), writing telegram bots (i.e.
<https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/gcal time track tg bot>,
), testing different neural nets architectures and learning new things.
# Experience
```

System Architect | Machine learning engineer | Software team leader at Remak

Dates Employed Jan 2016 - Jan 2020

Employment Duration 4 yrs 1 mos

Building a software platform to support new products and the company processes.

Team leadership:

- leading the team of 4 developers, learning from them
- specified sprint epics, controlling team progress, reporting to the client
- determining backend architecture and technological stack

Software developer:

- building async microservices (Python, aiohttp, Docker, openAPI ...)
 - with the normal pythonic worker
 - where worker was a CDLL of .NET assembly and applied different approaches in parallelization
 - numeric microservices where main worker was a numpy or pytorch model
 - Automate the openAPI spec definition with the help of swagger, attrs,

```
    unit, integration and load testing

    - primary with the pytest
    - API mocking

    integration testing for microservices based application

    documentation and code review

- setting up CI pipelines for linting, testing and building images
  Setting up automatic deployment system with a help of Gitlab runners,
docker-compose, shell scripting and Gitlab CI.
- Writing Ansible and Vagrant scripts to deploy the app on Kubernetes
- Containerization of a different applications for the needs of the team (
    i.e. special cli version of FreeCAD, image with pythonnet support on
    Linux and Mono, linux with wine integration to run windows assemblies on
    linux
- Building infrastructure automation for development and staging environments
- Setting up app monitoring with help of Gitlab CI, Sentry and some scripting
- Setting up app templating, pre-commit hooks for a team
**Machine learning engineer:**
- applying machine learning to improve user experience.
    - Particularly speeding up the calculation processes
    - Supervise learning, mostly with gradient boosting and partly with the
    combination of neural nets in PyTorch
    - applying optimization with evolutionary algorithms (SicPy + PyTorch)
## HVAC (heating, ventilation and air conditioning) proffesional
Dates Employed May 2006 - Aug 2016
Employment Duration 10 yrs 3 mos
I was working in a variety of positions within the HVAC industry
 Compact Air Handling Units (AHU) project manager (~ 1 year)
- AHU technical support (~1 year)
- HVAC designer (~5 years)

    Energy modeler for LEED certification (~ 1 year)

    Technical superviser on site (~1 years)

    Ventilation systems installer (~1 year)

# Projects
- Air handling units selection engine powered by machine learning
<https://gitlab.com/remak-dva/docker-freecad-cli>
- < https://gitlab.com/zhukovgreen/pozemky> - This is how I bought my home
- <<u>https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/gcal_time_track_tg_bot</u>> - This is how I used to
track my time
 Dog breed identification
<a href="https://qithub.com/ZhukovGreen/dog-project/blob/master/dog-app.ipynb">
  Reinforcement learning
< https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/machine-learning/blob/submission/smartcab/projects/
smartcab/smartcab/agent.py>
  Supervise learning problem <a href="https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/UMLND/blob/">https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/UMLND/blob/</a>
<u>d7a1326247705cac90120c266ca6296e7b19e257/finding_donors/finding_donors.ipynb</u>>
  PyTorch, transfer learning <a href="https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/pytorch-scholarship-">https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/pytorch-scholarship-</a>
challenge>
  Unsupervised learning problem
<a href="https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/machine-learning/blob/submission/costumer-seaments/">https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/machine-learning/blob/submission/costumer-seaments/</a>
projects/customer_segments/customer_segments.ipynb>
# Education
## Udacity
Degree Name Nano-degree
Field Of Study Machine Learning
Grade Nano-degree
Dates attended or expected graduation 2016 - 2018
```

marshmallow etc.

Stanford University Online

Degree Name Online Education

Field Of Study CS229: Machine Learning

Grade NA

Dates attended or expected graduation 2016 - 2017

I passed through all lectures videos and keynotes, resolved all assignments. Course syllabus: < http://cs229.stanford.edu/syllabus.html>

Donbass State Academy of Civil Engineering and Architecture

Degree Name Master's Degree Field Of Study Mechanical Engineering (HVAC) Grade M.Sc. in heating, ventilation, air conditioning systems Dates attended or expected graduation 2002 - 2008

Courses

Udacity: PyTorch Scholarship Challenge from Facebook A vast amount of different courses at Udemy, such as data structures and algorithms, PyTorch Reinforcement learning etc.

Languages

Russian - native English - good proffesional level Czech - good proffesional level

Social profiles

- GitHub <<u>https://github.com/zhukovgreen</u>>
- GitLab <<u>https://gitlab.com/zhukovgreen</u>>
- StackOverflow < https://stackoverflow.com/users/4351027/artem-zhukov>
- Twitter < https://twitter.com/zhukovgreen>
- LinkedIn < https://www.linkedin.com/in/artem-zhukov-0556b422/>